I was a professional driver for 2 years
until I had my license revoked after DUI.
I had to sell my business and my car,
and now I work a normal job.
And yet I cannot stop drinking
even when I know it's bad for me.
That's one issue.
Buddha is the one person
that gives me comfort.
Even when I'm drunk I look at Buddha
and I have no fear.
It might be wrong faith
but when in hard times,
I call this name
and tears come running down.
I want to be able to control myself
but it's not easy.
I seek your guidance so my seed of faith
can blossom into a flower.
You can't stop a single drinking habit
you've created in this lifetime.
How can you expect to stop karma
from many lifetimes?
I think I know how, but it's not easy.
My wife always calls me a fool.
I work hard but
I have no desire for wealth.
Hence my household remains poor.
She's right to call me a fool.
Not because I'm stupid
but because I like to have a good time.
If a person likes to fish,
that person doesn't think of it
as an illness, does he?
And yet how would the fish think of him?
(Questioner) To the fish, he's a murderer.
(Sunim) What about gamblers?
I can't stop gambling either.
To gamblers, it's just a hobby.
But to others, it's an illness.
You have an addiction
with alcohol, gambling and having fun.
Technically if you want to quit,
you'd quit.
But you can't stop.
This means you are addicted.
I keep getting dragged around by it.
(Sunim) Exactly.
That we call an addiction.
(Sunim) You are an addict.
What should I do?
(Sunim) You're not just getting dragged
around, you're an addict.
I need to drink at least a bottle of soju
to go to sleep when I'm tired.
(Sunim) I know. That is alcoholism.
When you're bored,
you'd need to play cards.
That again is an addiction.
How you quit... Do you even want to quit?
Aren't you subconsciously thinking,
'What fun is life
without drinking and gambling?'
The truth is, it is fun.
And yet why are you trying to quit?
Why not live as you are?
(Questioner) When I look at my kids and
family, I know I need to stop but I can't.
Then just tell your wife and kids
that you can't give up the fun.
Declare that you'll do you,
they should live their lives.
There are many homeless people
in front of the Seoul train station.
They are mostly alcoholic.
They'd rather live on the street
and beg than give up drinking.
The government provides them shelters,
yet shelters don't allow drinking.
Hence no one stays there.
They all leave.
They'd rather sleep on cardboard boxes
and drink soju than stay in shelters.
Even if you insist, they won't stay.
They'd ask firsthand
whether they can drink there or not.
(Questioner) I'm not quite
at that level yet.
How do you know you won't be there soon?
How many days
have you tried to go without drinking?
(Questioner) Recently I've been
drinking constantly.
(Questioner) But I didn't drink yesterday
for the whole day so I could see you.
Do you still work?
(Questioner) Yes.
Can you take leave for a week?
For about 5 days?
Not now.
I work on a fixed shift from 3am to 6pm.
I'm physically exhausted
after 14 hours of work.
I have no holidays, no Sundays off.
I have no time for anything else.
Because of the economy, there aren't
many jobs even for skilled workers.
I once ran my own business,
I'm a hard worker.
But I don't have any desire for money.
I don't understand why I don't.
So what are you going to do about it?
If you really want to quit,
you should try quitting for a week.
You should observe the inner turmoil
and overcome them.
And yet you claim you can't take
a single day off. I can't help you then.
When I went to
the Jungto Enlightenment Retreat,
I didn't smoke the whole time.
You went for Retreat and you still
weren't able to quit your addictions?
I was just about to suggest that
you attend a Meditation Retreat.
I will make time and attend.
(Sunim) Attend a Meditation Retreat
for a week in July.
You'll realize how serious
your addition is,
and how violent that karma is.
In Christian terms,
it will be more than Satan,
In Buddhist terms,
it will be more than Devils.
Once you precisely observe
how your karma makes you suffer
on the subconscious level,
you'll realize that you need to fix it.
As of now, your rational self
wants to fix it,
but your subconscious tells you,
'What fun is life
if I can't do these things?'
Hence you can't fix your habits.
(Sunim) Can you do
108 prostrations in the morning?
I can do that.
But I have to go to work
at 3 in the morning,
so I'd need to wake up an hour earlier.
(Sunim) No need to.
Then how about after work?
(Sunim) Can you not because
you'd be drinking after work?
Don't start drinking right after work.
Do prostrations first,
and then drink if you wish.
(Questioner) Okay.
Do 108 prostrations after work,
whether at work, at home,
or at a nearby temple.
And sincerely pray :
"Dear Buddha, I have forsaken
the vow I made from past life."
"Blinded by ignorance,
I am living in the shackles of my karma."
"Buddha, I will renew my vow."
"I came to this world not as an
unenlightened being, but as a bodhisattva."
"And yet I forgot that,
and I'm now living like this."
"I will remember and keep to my vow."
Pray like this.
Thank you.
(Sunim) Pray first, drink later.
I should quit.
Why quit something so enjoyable?
Don't force yourself
to think you should quit.
Think of praying first,
don't think too much about drinking.
Just pray every day.
After work, do your prayer.
Pray first, eat and drink later.
After prayers, drink if you want to.
Don't drink if not.
Resolutions don't last long anyway.
If you pray every day,
your subconscious will undergo change.
You'll drink but you'll drink less.
Then you'll go a day without drinking.
Changes will happen in such ways.
You came to this world to do something,
to walk the path of Enlightenment.
That's why you have no desire for money.
But somewhere along the way,
you've become lost.
You are now lost and
on a completely different path
If you pray and prostrate,
you can get back on track. Try it.